Bishoksan Kafle

Homepage: https://bishoksan.github.io

 $\label{linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/bishoksan-kafle-a96a7235} \mbox{ Mobile: } +61-414056159$

24/443 Pacific Hwy, Asquith, NSW 2077

E-mail: bishoksan@gmail.com

Professional Summary

• Result-oriented forward-thinking individual with demonstrated ability in academic research, in particular, automated software analysis and verification with 20+ peer-reviewed scientific publications and contribution to several state-of-the-art program analysers/verifiers.

- Excellent team player and strong builder of collaborations in different aspects of basic and applied research with 5+ international research projects participation, PC member/chair of 7 international conferences/workshops, reviewer of 4+ leading journals and accessor of ARC.
- Creative, focussed, detail-oriented and self-motivated individual with proven ability to lead projects and deliver results, and integrate easily in a multicultural and multilingual environment; with experience of working and studying in 5 different continents.

Relevant Skills

• Research expertise

- Strong research expertise as evidenced by 15+ first-authored peer-reviewed scientific publications (citations: 185, h-index: 9, i10-index: 9) in program analysis and verification, gained prior, during and after my PhD in leading universities and research institutes.
- Experience in large scale applied research as evidenced by participation in 5 international projects funded by the EU, ARC, Spanish and Italian government and working on resource analysis of avionic systems at intelligent system division, NASA.
- Expertise in program analysis and verification as evidenced by serving as program committee member of 7+ conferences, reviewer of 4+ leading journals and an accessor of the ARC.
- Strong programming (Java, C, C++, Python, Prolog, OCaml, SQL, web languages etc.), software engineering and data analysis skills as evidenced by several contributed research (https://github.com/bishoksan) and commercial (e-Sewa: https://esewa.com.np) tools, gained while working in industries and universities.

• Communication and networking skill

- Strong communication skills as evidenced by 30+ scientific presentations along with several enriching teaching and supervision experience in computer science.
- Strong networking skills as evidenced by 5+ active collaboration including in the US, EU, AU;
 24+ co-authors and tool developers, gained while studying, working, participating in projects, attending conferences and meetings.

Project management and leadership skill

 Leadership skills as evidenced by chairing workshop and meetings, editing workshop volume, planning, designing and teaching courses and managing projects. Project management skills as evidenced by timely achievement of project milestones, publications of research outcomes and distribution of prototype tools.

• Resource management and conflict resolution

- Resource management skills gained by setting up project websites and updating project
 evolution, creating document sharing repositories, supporting and guiding team members,
 preparing teaching materials and developing project ideas.
- Resource management skills as evidenced by co-authoring, timely publications of scientific articles and release of tools.
- Conflict resolution skills gained while resolving co-authorship, selectively publishing research outcomes and selecting appropriate tool licenses.

Work History

IMDEA Software Institute

Madrid, Spain

Research Fellow in Computer Science

2019-

- Computational resource analysis and verification, and recurrence equations solving:
 - * Excellent team work, collaboration and advanced knowledge of program analysis techniques led to 4 peer reviewed publications along with 3 state-of-the-art analysers PIHORN, NTHORN, TAGR-SOLVER, and
 - * also contributed to funding worth EUR 200,000+.

The University of Melbourne

Melbourne, Australia

Research Fellow in Computer Science

2016-2019

- Analysis and verification of programs manipulating fixed-with arithmetic, preconditions generation, decision procedures:
 - * Knowledge of current industry trends and team effort combined with expertise in constraint solving led to 6 peer reviewed publications along with 2 state-of-the-art constraint solvers SoMoLia, SoMoLia-QE, and 1 analyser PIHORN.
 - * also contributed to an ARC Discovery project proposal worth AUD 1.5+ million.

Roskilde University

Denmark

Research Associate in Computer Science

Nov. 2015 - Jun. 2016

Strong communication and resource management skills enabled to help organize several
activities (workshops, meetings, summer schools) to promote low energy computation and
collaborate with the partners in the ICT-ENERGY consortia.

NASA Ames Research Center, Intelligent system Division

California, USA

Visiting Research Scientist

March 2015 - Jun. 2015

 Excellent research environment under the guidance of world class researchers help plant the seed to the publication of 2 articles related to resource analysis and the development of resource analysis tool TAGR-SOLVER, which can be used for resource analysis of avionic systems.

Fondazione Bruno Kessler

Italy

Research Intern

Jul. 2011 - Sept. 2011

 Driven by product and market knowledge, implemented a knowledge store in Java for storing live memories such as photos, videos, lectures etc. F1 Soft International

Nepal 2009-2010

Software Developer

- Contributed to e-Sewa (a popular payment gateway widely used in Nepal driven by business acumen) and also to the development of banking softwares, web and mobile applications.

Education

Roskilde University

Denmark

PhD in Computer Science

2012 - 2016

- Thesis: Components for Automatic Horn clause Verification (Adv: Prof. J.P. Gallagher)

Dresden University of Technology

Germany, Italy, Portugal

European Masters in Computational Logic

2010 - 2012

- Thesis: Worst-case execution time of programs (Adv: Prof. P. Barahona & F. Cassez)

Research Projects

ProCode Project

Madrid, Spain

Spanish Ministry of Research, Science and Innovation (Role: Research fellow) involved: 2019-

Analysing Computer Arithmetic to Improve Software Reliability Melbourne, Australia

ARC discovery project DP14010294 (Role: Research fellow) involved: 2016 - 2019

ICT-Energy Coordination Action

Denmark

EU 7th Framework (Role: Research associate)

involved: Nov. 2015- Jun. 2016

ENTRA: Whole-Systems Energy Transparency

Denmark

EU 7th Framework (Role: PhD student)

involved: Dec.2012- Dec. 2015

LiveMemories: Active Digital Memories of Collective Lives

Italy

Provincia Autonoma di Trento (Role: MSc Intern)

involved: Jul.2011- Sep. 2011

Selected Publications (More [DBLP, Google Scholar])

Edited Books

B1. Hossein Hojjat & Bishoksan Kafle: Proceedings 8th Workshop on Horn Clauses for Verification and Synthesis. 2021. EPTCS vol. 344. ISSN: 2075-2180.

Refereed Journals

- J1. Bishoksan Kafle, Graeme Gange, Peter J. Stuckey, Peter Schachte & Harald Søndergaard: Transformation-enabled precondition inference. TPLP. 2021 (to appear).
- J2. Bishoksan Kafle, John P. Gallagher, Graeme Gange et al.: An iterative approach to precondition inference using constrained Horn clauses. TPLP. 2018.
- J3. Bishoksan Kafle, John P. Gallagher & Pierre Ganty: Tree dimension in verification of constrained Horn clauses. TPLP. 2018.
- J4. John P. Gallagher, Mai Ajspur & Bishoksan Kafle: Optimised determinisation and completion of finite tree automata. J. Log. Algebr. Meth. Program. 2018.

- J5. Bishoksan Kafle & John P. Gallagher: Constraint specialisation in Horn clause verification. Sci. Comput. Program. 2017.
- J6. Bishoksan Kafle & John P. Gallagher: Horn clause verification with convex polyhedral abstraction and tree automata-based refinement. J. Comp. Lang., Systems & Structures. 2017.
- J7. Kerstin Eder, ..., Bishoksan Kafle et. al: *ENTRA: Whole-systems energy transparency*. Microprocessors and Microsystems Embedded Hardware Design. 2016.

Refereed Conferences and workshops

- C1. Bishoksan Kafle, Graeme Gange, Peter Schachte, Harald Søndergaard & Peter J. Stuckey: Lightweight Nontermination Inference with CHCs. SEFM. 2021 (to appear).
- C2. Bishoksan Kafle, John P. Gallagher, Manuel V. Hermenegildo et al.: Regular Path Clauses and Their Application in Solving Loops. HCVS. 2021.
- C3. John P. Gallagher, Manuel V. Hermenegildo, Bishoksan Kafle et al.: From Big-Step to Small-Step Semantics and Back with Interpreter Specialisation. VPT/HCVS. 2020.
- C4. Bishoksan Kafle, Graeme Gange, Peter Schachte, Harald Sondergaard & Peter J. Stuckey: A Benders Decomposition Approach to Deciding Modular Linear Integer Arithmetic. SAT. 2017.
- C5. Bishoksan Kafle, John P. Gallagher & José F. Morales: RAHFT: A tool for verifying Horn clauses using abstract interpretation and finite tree automata. CAV. 2016.
- C6. Bishoksan Kafle & John P. Gallagher: Constraint Specialisation in Horn Clause Verification. PEPM. 2015. (Best Paper Award).
- C7. Bishoksan Kafle & John P. Gallagher: Tree automata-based refinement with application to Horn clause verification. VMCAI. 2015.
- C8. John P. Gallagher & Bishoksan Kafle: Analysis and Transformation Tools for Constrained Horn Clause Verification. ICLP. 2014.

Additional information

- **Personal interests:** Traveling, Languages, Philosophy and Mysticism, Meditation, Mind power, Volunteering.
- Character: Good interpersonal and communication skills, good team player, social, adventurous.
- Countries studied or worked: Australia, Spain, Denmark, United States, Germany, Italy, Portugal, Cuba, Nepal.
 - Languages: Nepali (mother tongue), English (fluent), Spanish (fluent), Portuguese (basic), Italian (basic), German (basic), Danish (basic), Hindi (basic).